Miguel ALVAREZ APARICIO

Address: Veerenni 19 - 13, 10135, Tallinn (Estonia)

Phone: +372 58142083 Email: malvarezap@gmail.com

Birthdate: 16-12-1983 Toledo (Spain) **Driving licence:** B, B1 (12/11/2002)

Marital Status: Married Nationality: Spanish

Portfolio: www.malvarezap.com



Employment History

Employer Period of Employment Position Held

Äripäev October 2015 - Infographic designer

Duties and Responsibilities:

• Creating explanatory graphics from economic data for web articles

Designing and coding interactive stories for the web

• Design of material for marketing campaings

Bronze medal in 2017 Estonian Press Assosiation (EALL) "Best digital story"

Employer Period of Employment Position Held

Snowcat Systems August 2013 - August 2015 Technical writer/Designer

Duties and Responsibilities:

• Image Processing and Mockups creation

Writing and designing User Manual, Released Notes, and Catalogues

• Design website and write contents: www.snowcatgames.com; www.estoniainternational.com

• Translations English - Spanish and Spanish - English

Employer Period of Employment Position Held
Teinteresa.es August 2012 - February 2013 Graphic designer

Duties and Responsibilities:

• Design visual elements of the webs

Design banners

Making the layout for tablets and smartphones

Employer Period of Employment Position Held

The Economist Magazine 2009 and 2010 Layout and graphic designer

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Adapt the annual english version of "The World in ..." to the spanish edition.

- Layout design

- Photographic editing and retouching.

- Illustrating.



Between 2015 and 2020 I have worked for my own design company MAZ OÜ designing websites, magazines and posters for different events and companies.

Between 2005 and 2010, I worked on different roles as a journalist: Movie critic, announcer, reporter, editor. As well, movie and sound edition in different places such as Radio Nacional de Espana (RNE) or Radio Marca (Unidad Editorial).

Education

Institution Period of Study Award

Istituto Europeo di Design, Spain 2011 – 2012 Editorial Design: Digital and

Printed Media, Master's Degree

Universidad Complutense de Madrid, Spain 2002–2009 Master's Degree in Journalism

Additional Training

2010 European Volunteer Service's Youth Pass, European Union

Bio

My name is Miguel Álvarez Aparicio and I'm a Spanish graphic designer. I was born in Toledo (Spain) however I moved to Madrid when I turned 18 in order to study Journalism at the UCM (Universidad Complutense de Madrid). After finishing my studies and making internships in several medias I ended up working with the layout of a national Spanish magazine called Tiempo. At the same time I started doing the layout for the Spanish version of the yearly special number of The Economist, The World in... for the years 2010 and 2011.

After that I lived in Bogotá (Colombia) for a while. Over there I decided that I need to improve my skills in design. Once I moved back I started a Master's degree in Editorial Design at the Istituto Europeo di Design. At that time I started testing myself in all the different areas of graphic design: magazines, books, web, apps, illustration, branding or UI/UX.

Since 2015 I work as a graphic editor for the web version of the economic newspaper Äripäev. Here I have expanded my experience in digital design and experimented with interactive graphics and data driven graphics. At the same time I have made several works with my own design studio, MAZ Design, in printed magazines, websites and branding.

Language and computer skills

Fluent written and spoken English

Spanish (Native language)

Estonian B1

Graphic design, Mac and PC environment: InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Hype Tumult 3

HTML, CSS, Javascript, SVG, Chartis, jQuery

Excellent computer literacy (Windows XP and 2000). Highly competent user of Microsoft Office (Word,

Excel and PowerPoint) and Google Docs

Working environment: JIRA, Confluence, Github.